The world is filled with despair.
العالم مليء باليأس
When you lose your way, I want you to rely on me.
عندما تضلّين طريقك، أريدك أن تعتمدي عليّ
Shizu-sensei...
...شيزو-سينسي
Chief Knight of the Imperial Guard, Holy Knight Captain Hinata Sakaguchi.
يا رئيسة فرسان الحرس الإمبراطوري، قائدة القدّيسين العشرة هيناتا ساكاغوتشي
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
The merchant from the east has brought the new book.
التاجر القادم من الشّرق أحضر الكتاب الجديد
Very well.
حسناً
A nation of monsters,
،دولة وحوش
the Jura Tempest Federation...
...اتّحاد جورا تيمبيست
Jura Tempest Federation
اتّحاد جورا تيمبيست
The Great Forest of Jura stretches across the center
تمتدّ غابة جورا العظيمة عبر مركز
of the eastern part of the continent.
الجزء الشرقيّ من القارّة
With Goblins, Ogres, Orcs, Lizardmen, and more,
بوجود الغوبلن والغيلان والأورك ورجال ،السّحالي والمزيد
a wide variety of monster species called this forest home
تشكيلة مُختلِفة واسعة من الوحوش أطلقت على هذه الغابة اسم الدّيار
when the new nation was suddenly built in it.
.عندما تأسّست الدولة الجديدة فجأة فيها
A nation of monsters: Tempest.
دولة من الوحوش: تيمبيست
The city is clean and well-maintained for comfortable living.
المدينة نظيفة ومُهيّأة لحياة رغيدة
Its residents are educated in reading, writing, arithmetic, and other subjects,
سكّانها يجيدون القراءة والكتابة وعلم ،الحساب ومجالات أخرى
and they produce weapons, armor, silk, and other products with well-trained skills.
ويصنعون الأسلحة والدّروع والحرير ومُنتجات أخرى بمهارات مُتقنة
Armed Nation of Dwargon
دولة دوارغون المُسلّحة
The Armed Nation of Dwargon, a nation of Dwarves
دولة دوارغون المُسلّحة، دولة الأقزام
ruled by Gazel Dwargo,
،يحكمها غازيل دوارغو
Kingdom of Blumund
مملكة بلوموند
and the Kingdom of Blumund, a nation of humans,
،ومملكة بلوموند، دولة البشر
have established friendships with it.
قد أسّست علاقات وطيدة معها
It also participates in trading and enjoys a stable economy.
تشارك أيضاً في التّجارة وتتمتّع باقتصاد مستقرّ
Its influence grows by the day.
ويزداد نفوذها يوماً بعد يوم
The leader of this nation of monsters, the Jura Tempest Federation...
...قائد دولة الوحوش هذه، اتّحاد جورا تيمبيست
is named Rimuru Tempest.
يُدعى ريمورو تيمبيست
Rimuru...
...ريمورو
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
ذلك الوقت الذي خُلقت فيه من جديد كهُلام
I'm Rimuru Tempest.
اسمي ريمورو تيمبيست
Digression: Hinata Sakaguchi
هيناتا ساكاغوتشي
As you can see, I'm a slime.
كما ترون، أنا هُلام
But I used to be a human.
لكن كنتُ بشريّاً
Sure is peaceful...
يا للهدوء
This is the former me.
هذا أنا سابقاً
Mikami Satoru, age 37,
،ميكامي ساتورو، العمر 37
and a virg—
—وأعز
I was a pretty good-looking guy, if I do say so myself.
كنتُ رجلاً وسيماً إن جاز التّعبير
Yeah, I think I was. Don't you?
أجل، أظنّني كنتُ كذلك. أتوافقونني؟
You do, right?
توافقونني، صحيح؟
I was a fairly capable employee at a major general contracting firm.
كنتُ موظّفاً مؤهّلاً نسبيّاً في شركة مقاولات عامّة كُبرى
But...
...لكن
Tamura!
!تامورا
S-Senpai!
!سـ-سينباي
I was stabbed in a random attack...
...طُعِنتُ بهجوم عشوائيّ
and died.
ومتّ
And then...
...ثمّ
for some reason, I was reincarnated in another world as a slime.
لسبب ما، خُلِقتُ في عالم آخر من جديد كهُلام
And that's what happened.
وهذا ما حدث
I am the Storm Dragon, Veldora.
أنا تنّين العاصفة، فيلدورا
Storm Dragon?
تنّين العاصفة؟
I am one of only four True Dragons that exist in this world.
أنا واحد من التّنانين الحقيقيّة الأربعة الوحيدة الموجودة في هذا العالم
Veldora was the first friend I made in this world.
كان فيلدورا أوّل صديق تعرّفتُ عليه في هذا العالم
Please grant us your protection!
!امنحنا حمايتك أرجوك
If you do, we will swear our loyalty to you!
!إن فعلت، سنقسم الولاء لك
We will swear!
!سنقسم
In lieu of the Storm Dragon Veldora,
،بالنيابة عن تنّين العاصفة فيلدورا
I, Rimuru Tempest, will grant your wish!
!أنا، ريمورو تيمبيست، أمنحكما أمنيتكما
In some bizarre twist, I became the protector of the Goblins...
في تحوّل أحداث غريب، أصبحتُ ...حامي الغوبلن
Our pack yields to you.
يرضخ قطيعنا لك
And then I became the head of a Direwolf pack.
ثمّ أصبحتُ رئيس قطيع ذئاب رهيبة
Please accept our allegiance.
اقبل ولاءنا من فضلك
We will continue to serve you.
سنستمرّ في خدمتك
You're sure?
متأكّدون؟
I have no objections.
لا اعتراض لديّ
We are truly fortunate to have met you.
نحن حقّاً محظوظون لالتقائنا بك
I'm your secretary and bodyguard, Great Rimuru!
!أنا سكرتيرتك وحارستك الشخصيّة يا ريمورو-ساما
I'll never leave your side!
!لن أتخلّى عنك أبداً
Not until the ends of our lives.
حتّى الرّمق الأخير من حياتنا
O-Okay...
...حـ-حسناً
And before I knew what was happening,
،وقبل أن أستوعب ما كان يجري
I was revered as the head of the Ogres, Orcs, and all kinds of other races.
وجدتُ نفسي مُقدّساً كرئيس الغيلان والأورك ومُختلف الأجناس الأخرى
Then our nation shall be called the Jura Tempest Federation,
،إذاً يجب أن تُدعى دولتنا اتّحاد جورا تيمبيست
and this town shall be called Rimuru!
!وأن تُدعى هذه البلدة ريمورو
Capital City Rimuru!
!المدينة العاصمة ريمورو
Hang on, that's kinda embarrassi—
—مهلاً، هذا محرج بعض الشـ
No other name would do!
!لا يوجد اسم أفضل من هذا
I agree. It's a perfect name for our town.
أتّفق. إنّه اسم مثاليّ لبلدتنا
Since I had become this nation's leader,
،منذ أصبحتُ قائد هذه الدّولة
I made up my mind to protect all my allies
قرّرتُ أن أحمي حلفائي
and make Tempest a safe, prosperous, comfortable city to live in.
وأجعل تيمبيست مدينة آمنة ومزدهرة ومريحة للعيش
And then, somehow...
...ثمّ، بطريقة ما
I ended up becoming a school teacher.
أصبحتُ أستاذ مدرسة في النّهاية
This is the Kingdom of Ingrassia.
هذه مملكة إنغراشيا
Kingdom of Ingrassia
مملكة إنغراشيا
It's the leading cultural center of the western part of the continent,
،إنّها المركز الثّقافي الرّائد للجزء الغربيّ من القارّة
as well as a large, vibrant nation.
وكذلك دولة حيويّة وضخمة
There, a mutual aid organization for adventurers, the Free Union,
هناك، أسّست منظّمة إعانة تبادليّة ،للمُغامرين، الاتّحاد الحرّ
established Freedom Academy to nurture and teach its members.
أكاديميّةَ الحرّية لتربية وتعليم أعضائها
And that's where...
...وهناك حيث
I was appointed to teach a class of problematic kids.
تعيّنتُ لتعليم صفّ من الأطفال الأشقياء
The five of them were the regret that Shizu-san had left behind.
كان أولئك الخمسة الحسرة التي ظلّت تلازم شيزو-سان بعد رحيلها
Shizu-san had come to this world from Japan, just like me.
كانت شيزو-سان قد أتت إلى هذا العالم من اليابان، مثلي تماماً
I reincarnated here after dying in Japan,
،خُلِقتُ هنا من جديد بعد الموت في اليابان
but Shizu-san was a Summon, meaning she had been summoned here...
لكن كانت شيزو-سان مُستدعاة، ما يعني ...أنّها استُدعيَت إلى هنا
by the Demon Lord Leon Cromwell.
بواسطة سيّد الشّياطين ليون كرومويل
I thought she was useless, but she may have an affinity for fire.
ظننتُها ضعيفة، لكن ربّما لديها تجانُس مع النّار
Ifrit, I offer her body to you.
إيفريت، أقدّم جسدها لك
Use it well.
استخدمه كيفما تشاء
A Summon, as the name suggests,
،المُستدعى، كما يشير الاسم
is someone who was summoned into this world.
هو شخص استُدعي إلى هذا العالم
A Summon?
مُستدعى؟
Is that different from Otherworlders?
هل هذا مختلف عن العابِر من عالم آخر؟
It takes more than 30 mages to perform a ritual that lasts several days
يتطلّب الأمر أكثر من 30 ساحراً لأداء طقوس تدوم عدّة أيّام
to bring one here from another world.
لإحضار شخص إلى هنا من عالم آخر
They're also expected to serve as powerful weapons.
يؤمل منهم كذلك أن يؤدّوا وظيفتهم كأسلحة قوية
Weapons?
أسلحة؟
Yes, for the Summoner.
أجل، بالنسبة للمُستدعي
Magic is used to carve a curse into the Summon's soul
يُستخدم السّحر لنقش لعنة في روح المُستدعى
to ensure that the Summon can't defy the Summoner.
لضمان عدم عصيانه للمُستدعي
What the heck?! That's just cruel!
!ماذا؟! هذا قاسٍ جدّاً
Cruel, eh?
قاسٍ؟
I don't know what your world was like,
،لا أعرف كيف الأمور في عالمك
but survival of the fittest is the prevailing truth in this world.
لكن البقاء للأفضل هو الحقيقة السّائدة في هذا العالم
I see...
هكذا إذاً
Shizu-san remained in service to the Demon Lord Leon.
ظلّت شيزو-سان تخدم سيّد الشّياطين ليون
Whether that's because of a curse or because of the fire spirit Ifrit
،سواء كان السّبب هو لعنة أو روح النّار إيفريت
was unclear, even to Shizu-san herself.
فهذا غير معروف حتّى بالنسبة لشيزو-سان نفسها
Several years passed.
مضت سنوات عديدة
After an intense battle,
،بعد معركة حامية
the Demon Lord abandoned his castle and vanished somewhere,
،غادر سيّد الشّياطين قلعته واختفى
leaving Shizu-san behind.
تاركاً شيزو-سان لوحدها
I can't beat her...
...لا أستطيع هزيمتها
Shizu-san was then taken in by the Hero.
تمّ تبنّي شيزو-سان بعدها بواسطة البطلة
She traveled with the Hero for years...
...سافرت مع البطلة لسنوات
and even after they parted ways,
،وحتّى بعد فراقهما
she traveled the world as an adventurer to save people who were suffering.
سافرت حول العالم كمُغامرة لإنقاذ النّاس الذين كانوا يعانون
Eventually, she became known as a Champion.
في نهاية المطاف، عُرِفَت باسم النّصيرة
But as she grew older, her magic weakened,
،لكن مع كِبَرها في السنّ، ضَعُف سحرها
and she began to lose control over Ifrit.
وبدأت تفقد السّيطرة على إيفريت
She didn't want to risk hurting anyone she cared about,
،لم ترد المُخاطرة بأذيّة من تحبّهم
so she retired from adventuring and became a teacher at Freedom Academy.
لذلك اعتزلت المُغامرة وأصبحت مُدرّسة في أكاديميّة الحرّية
Among her students was Yuuki Kagurazaka,
،من بين تلاميذها كان يوكي كاغورازاكا
who became the Grandmaster of the adventurers' guild.
والذي أصبح رئيس نقابة المُغامرين
I heard that there was another who left Shizu-san's side,
،سمعتُ أنّ هناك شخص آخر ترك شيزو-سان
but her last batch of students...
...لكن دُفعة تلاميذها الأخيرة
Yes, Kenya Misaki,
،أجل، كينيا ميساكي
Ryota Sekiguchi,
،ريوتا سيكيغوتشي
Gale Gibson,
،غيل غيبسون
Alice Rondo,
،آليس روندو
and Chloe Aubert...
...وكلوي أوبيرت
were all Summons from the world I had come from.
كلّهم تمّ استدعاؤهم من العالم الذي أتيتُ منه
What're we gonna do today, Sensei?
ماذا سنفعل اليوم يا سينسي؟
That's a good question. What should we do today?
هذا سؤال وجيه. ماذا ينبغي أن نفعل اليوم؟
But then,
،بعد ذلك
Shizu-san sensed that she didn't have long left to live...
شعرت شيزو-سان أنّه لم يبقَ من عمرها الكثير
and she set out on her final journey.
وشرعت في رحلتها الأخيرة
So, do you like our town?
هل تحبّين بلدتنا إذاً؟
Yes, very much.
أجل، كثيراً
You're welcome to stay as long as you'd like, Shizu-san.
مرحّب ببقائكِ هنا كما تشائين يا شيزو-سان
Thank you... but I have to go.
شكراً لك... لكن عليّ الذهاب
You do?
حقّاً؟
If I stay here, I might bring trouble for you.
إذا بقيتُ هنا، فقد أسبّب المتاعب لكم
The goal of my journey is...
...هدف رحلتي هو
Goal?
هدف؟
...to find the man who summoned me.
إيجاد الشّخص الذي استدعاني
What will you do when you find him?
ماذا ستفعلين عندما تجدينه؟
She wanted to see the Demon Lord Leon Cromwell again.
أرادت رؤية سيّد الشّياطين ليون كرومويل ثانية
But she couldn't fulfill that goal.
لكن لم تستطع تحقيق ذلك الهدف
Take this! Icicle Shotgun!
!خذوا هذه! بندقيّة الماء المتجمّد
She could no longer restrain Ifrit,
،لم تعد قادرة على كبح جماح إيفريت
and then...
...ثمّ
Hey, Slime-san, what's your name?
هلام-سان، ما اسمك؟
Huh? I told you, I'm Rimuru.
أخبرتُك، اسمي ريمورو
No, I mean your real name.
لا، أعني اسمك الحقيقي
It's Satoru. Mikami Satoru.
اسمي ساتورو. ميكامي ساتورو
I'm Shizue. Izawa Shizue.
وأنا شيزوي. إيزاوا شيزوي
Shizue-san, you should sleep now.
شيزوي-سان، ينبغي أن تنامي الآن
Satoru-san, I'd like to ask a favor.
ساتورو-سان، أرغب في طلب معروف
May I?
هل يمكنني؟
Of course. Ask me anything.
بالطبع. اسأليني أي شيء
Please...
...أرجوك
eat me.
كلني
Just like you ate the curse that had been cast on me.
مثلما أكلتَ اللّعنة التي استُخدمت عليّ
That made me so happy.
أسعدني ذلك كثيراً
I dislike this world...
...لا أحبّ هذا العالم
Still, I can't abhor it.
رغم ذلك، لا أستطيع كرهه
Just like that man...
...مثل ذلك الرّجل تماماً
So... That's why...
...لذا... لهذا السبب
I don't want to be absorbed by this world.
لا أريد أن يمتصّني هذا العالم
This is... my last request.
هذا... طلبي الأخير
Would you... let me rest inside you?
هلّا... جعلتني أستقرّ داخلك؟
Okay.
حسناً
I swear to you on the name of Mikami Satoru... no, Rimuru Tempest,
،أقسم لك باسم ميكامي ساتورو... لا ،باسم ريمورو تيمبيست
that I will make certain the Demon Lord Leon Cromwell hears your wishes!
أنّني سأحرص على أن يصغي سيّد الشّياطين ليون كرومويل لأمنياتك
Thank... you...
...شكراً... لك
Shizu-san, my destined one...
...شيزو-سان، أيّتها المُقدّرة لي
Rest in peace within me.
ارقدي بسلام داخلي
Use unique skill "Predator"?
استخدم المهارة الفريدة "مُفترس"؟
Yes.
أجل
So that she can dream happy dreams forever and never have to wake from them.
وذلك كي ترى أحلاماً سعيدة للأبد ولا تصحو منها أبداً
You intend to interfere with my plans,
،أتنوي عرقلة مخطّطاتي
leader of the Great Forest of Jura, Rimuru Tempest?
يا قائد غابة جورا العظيمة، ريمورو تيمبيست؟
Orcs.
الأورك
I had the idea to use those starved pigs to strengthen my forces, but...
جاءتني فكرة استخدام أولئك الخنازير ...المتضوّرين جوعاً لتعزيز قوايّ، لكن
I've acknowledged you as an enemy.
اعترفتُ بك عدوّاً
Now I'll take you on for real.
والآن سأواجهك بجدّية
Laughable!
!هذا مثير للضحك
Does that mean you weren't serious before now?
هل هذا يعني أنّك لم تكن جادّاً قبل الآن؟
There is nothing more you can do!
!لا يسعك فعل المزيد
Just accept that I'm going to eat you!
!تقبّل أنّني سآكلك فحسب
Before you can eat me, I'm going to eat you.
قبل أن تتمكّن من أكلي، سوف آكلك
I'm a slime.
أنا هُلام
Wha—
—ما
Wh-Why, you...
أيّها الوغد
You're not the only one who can eat things!
!لست الوحيد القادر على أكل الأشياء
Will you eat me first...
...هل ستأكلني
or will I eat you first?
أم سآكلك أوّلاً؟
The one who completely consumes the other wins!
!من يلتهم الآخر كلّياً هو من يربح
I never even imagined that you would interfere.
لم أتخيّل أبدّاً أن تتدخّل وتعرقل مخطّطاتي
Even though I sent out the resurrected Charybdis after that,
على الرّغم من إرسالي للكاريبديس ،المنبعثين بعد ذلك
the Demon Lord Milim joined their side...
...انضمّت سيّدة الشّياطين ميليم لصفّهم
I've already seen that trick.
كشفتُ هذه الخدعة سلفاً
Now, I'll show you one of mine.
سأريك خدعتي الآن
This is...
...هذا
what you call "restraint"!
!"ما يُدعى بـ"التحفّظ
Drago Buster!
!دراغو باستر
Well, no matter.
حسناً، لا يهمّ
I will make use of Milim soon enough.
سأستفيد من ميليم قريباً
As for that slime... Rimuru, as I believe he is called...
...بالنسبة لذلك الهُلام... ريمورو حسبما أعتقد اسمه
I will see that he disappears
سأحرص على أن يزول
along with his beloved nation of Tempest and everyone dear to him.
هو ودولته تيمبيست العزيزة وكلّ الأعزّاء على قلبه
He has truly started to become a nuisance of late.
بدأ يصبح مصدر إزعاج مؤخّراً
Since he chose to interfere with the Demon Lord Clayman,
،بما أنّه اختار أن يقف في وجه سيّد الشّياطين كلايمان
I must assume he is prepared for the consequences.
يجب أن أفترض أنّه مستعدّ للعواقب
Shizu-san's lingering regret
حسرة شيزو-سان طويلة الأمد
was the five kids who were summoned into this world.
كانت الأطفال الخمسة الذين تمّ استدعاؤهم إلى هذا العالم
When a summoning is performed, there are times when a child is summoned.
عندما يُجرى استدعاء، يُستدعى طفل في بعض الأوقات
And when an amount of energy too vast
وعندما تكون الطّاقة هائلة جدّاً
for that child's growing body is taken in...
...على أن يتحمّلها جسد الطفل النّامي
Eventually, that body will be incinerated by all that energy with nowhere to go.
في نهاية المطاف، سيحترق ذلك الجسد بواسطة الطّاقة التي لا تجد منفساً لها
No one has found a way to prevent their destruction.
لم يجد أحدٌ وسيلة لمنع دمارهم
Nearly all children under the age of ten who have been summoned
تقريباً كافّة الأطفال تحت سنّ العاشرة الذين تمّ استدعاؤهم
have died within five years.
قد ماتوا في غضون خمس سنوات
Please!
!أرجوك
If it's at all possible, please save those children!
!إن كان ذلك ممكناً، أنقذ أولئك الأطفال
I'll just do whatever I can.
سأفعل ما يمكنني فعله
It's what I've always done, and what I'll continue to do.
هذا ما كنتُ أفعله دوماً، وما سأستمرّ في فعله
That was when I thought...
...حينها قد فكّرت
Shizu-san was also summoned as a child,
،كانت شيزو-سان مُستدعاة أيضاً كطفلة
but she lived.
لكنّها عاشت
Was it because housing Ifrit within her body
هل كان ذلك لأنّ استضافة جسدها لإيفريت
enabled her to control the energy she had inside her?
أتاح لها التحكّم بالطاقة التي كانت تحتويها؟
So I decided to get spirits to dwell in the kids' bodies,
،لهذا قررتُ جعل أرواح تسكن أجساد الاطفال
and we headed to the Dwelling of Spirits.
وتوجّهنا إلى مسكن الأرواح
Our goal was to capture superior spirits.
كان هدفنا أسر الأرواح العُليا
In the Dwelling of Spirits, we got the Queen of Spirits, Ramiris, to help us.
في مسكن الأرواح، طلبنا من ملكة الأرواح راميريس مساعدتنا
Right!
!حسناً
Kenya, Ryota, Gale, Alice, Chloe...
...كينيا، ريوتا، غيل، آليس، كلوي
Let's do this!
!لنفعل هذا
Yeah!
!نعم
Shizu-san, wherever you are, are you watching?
شيزو-سان، أينما كنتِ، هل تشاهدين؟
I'll make sure your wish is realized.
سأحرص على تحقيق أمنيتك
And then...
...ثمّ
I helped each of the kids house a spirit,
،ساعدتُ كلّ طفل في استضافة روح
successfully stabilizing the magicules in their bodies.
لتستقرّ الجزيئات السحريّة في أجسادهم بنجاح
Although I'm not sure what the one that took up residence in Chloe was...
رغم أنّني لستُ متأكّداً من ماهيّة ...الرّوح التي سكنت كلوي
But it worked out, so it's not a problem!
!لكن نجح الأمر، لذا ليست مشكلة
Yep! All's well that ends well!
!أجل! الأمور بخواتمها
I did it, Shizu-san.
فعلتُها يا شيزو-سان
They'll be okay now.
إنّهم بخير الآن
With that, Shizu-san's lingering regret was resolved.
وبهذا تكون حسرة شيزو-سان طويلة الأمد قد زالت
And they all lived happily ever after!
!وعاشوا جميعهم بسعادة من بعد ذلك
At least, that's what I thought.
على الأقلّ، هذا ما ظننتُه
But I had no idea that an unimaginable disaster
لكن لم أكن أدري أنّ كارثة لا يمكن تصوّرها
was about to strike Tempest, my allies, and me personally...
كانت على وشك أن تضرب تيمبيست وحلفائي وأنا شخصيّاً
and that disaster would be brought to us
وأنّ تلك الكارثة ستنزل علينا
by Shizu-san's former student, Hinata Sakaguchi.
بواسطة تلميذة شيزو-سان السّابقة، هيناتا ساكاغوتشي
Rimuru Tempest... and Shizu-sensei?
ريمورو تيمبيست... وشيزو-سينسي؟
I see. So you...
...فهمت. إذاً أنت
killed Shizu-sensei.
من قتل شيزو-سينسي